NARRATOR: Previously on Gotham:
- You need to leave Ms. Kringle alone.
- I get it now.
You got a thing for my girl.
[GRUNTS]
Oh, dear.
[LAUGHS]
Who sent you?
You want me to tell
Bunderslaw that you're onto him?
[SCREAMS]
- I'm Bruce Wayne.
- Sid Bunderslaw.
The people of Gotham deserve to know that
there is a serial killer in their midst.
I'm coming after you.
He murders the loved ones of
any cop who investigates him.
Care to dance?
Morning. How'd you sleep?
The hour we slept?
Great.
You hungry? I have quiche.
No, thanks.
At least have some coffee.
Let me tell you about the
day I have planned for us.
- I think I'm just gonna get out of here.
- Wait.
We had fun last night, right?
Stay.
- Listen, you don't have to do this.
- Do what?
Last night at the ball,
you talked a good game.
But let's not pretend this
is more than what it is.
Barbara, I'm not
pretending with you.
I want you to stay with me.
I don't think so.
Wait, wait, wait.
Let go.
Look...
I was pretending with you.
But not in the way you think.
[SIGHS]
The night we met...
I was going to kill you.
That's not funny.
But then...
I saw something in you.
Barbara, I saw...
the real you.
You're the woman that I
have been searching for.
You're lying.
I'm gonna let you go now.
And you're going to sit down...
and have breakfast with me.
[GRUNTS]
No!
So we'll do it the hard way.
- Hey. How are you doing?
- I've been better.
- Have you seen Harvey?
- No. Any word on Barbara?
They haven't found her body yet,
so there's a chance she's still alive.
- When's the last time you slept?
- I don't know.
Last time you ate?
I don't know.
I know better than to
try to get you to sleep.
- But you really should eat.
- I'm not hungry.
Jim.
It's not your fault.
I did this. I pressed Loeb, he sent
the Ogre after me, and I didn't stop.
It's bad enough I knowingly put you in
danger. I didn't even think of Barbara.
- You were doing your job.
- But I should've known.
How? You weren't together.
Do you blame yourself
for falling out of love?
Lee, it's my responsibility. There's
nothing you can say that changes that.
Whatever happens
to Barbara, it's on me.
- I understand. BULLOCK: Jimbo.
Meet Jake the JV pimp.
He's been bragging that
he knows who the Ogre is.
I keep telling you, man, you
been lied to. I don't know nothing.
- Yeah, we'll see about that.
- Unh.
Okey-doke.
No body, no crime.
Nope. Never seen him before.
We think this is a serial
killer called the Ogre.
He's kidnapped a woman,
and he's gonna kill her...
unless we find him first.
Bummer.
Just so you understand...
the lady in question is a
real good friend of ours.
Supposing, for the sake of
argument, I did see him before.
What's she worth?
Yeah, you know...
if you had to assign
a dollar amount.
Harvey, I'm about to violate departmental
policy on interrogation techniques.
I think I saw some doughnuts
outside with my name all over them.
Hey, now. Calm yourself.
There's no need to...
Jake worked as a barman at
a brothel called the Foxglove.
Said the Ogre was a regular.
Can't give us a location.
Because they never
use the same place twice.
- You know it?
- Not personally.
The Foxglove is very
high-class, very extreme.
You gotta know someone
who knows someone.
- I might know someone.
- You talking Penguin?
Get any deeper with that
clown, he will own you.
I don't have a choice.
The Ogre has Barbara.
Let me shake a few trees.
Take the time, grab
some Z's. You're burnt.
The first one was the hardest.
But it wasn't her fault.
She just wasn't the one.
I also couldn't let her go.
Still, it strengthened my resolve to
never stop till I found my soul mate...
the person I could
share everything with.
I think that person is you,
Barbara. But I need your help.
So...
let's begin again, shall we?
[MUFFLED SCREAM]
This just, um, came for you
by messenger, Master Bruce.
Thank you.
Right, well, I ought to be off.
Do you want company?
To identify Reggie? No, I
don't think so. Best done alone.
I'm sorry, Alfred.
- I know he was your friend.
- Just doesn't make any sense.
Reggie topping
himself like that.
You said he fell out of a window. He
might have been drinking, lost his balance.
[SCOFFS]
That Reggie was a legend.
He could be blind drunk
and walk a tightrope.
It doesn't matter what
he was like in the end.
I wanna see he gets
a proper send-off.
I'll see you this evening, sir.
LIDIA: What? Your boss
doesn't trust his partners?
It's called due diligence. He just
wants me to look the place over.
So look.
I got a gravy going.
Special party today.
Don't let me keep you.
Piece of work.
BUTCH: I put the pistol under the
bar, machine gun behind the juke.
All Connor and his guy
gotta do is get to them.
The day is finally here.
Maroni...
Jim. So lovely to see you.
To what do I owe this
wonderful surprise?
I need to know where the
Foxglove is. And I need an invitation.
[LAUGHING]
Well, someone's in a mood.
Can you help me out? Yes or no?
Jim, I do so love our
give-and-take relationship.
But it's starting to
feel a bit one-sided.
Fine. I'll owe you a favor.
- You already do.
- Then I'll owe you another.
Cards on the table?
The Foxglove makes a lot of
money for some important...
[GASPS]
You think you know who
I am, what I'm capable of?
You have no idea.
Today's an important day for me.
So I will accommodate
your request.
But, detective, mark my words...
you owe me a big favor.
[CHUCKLES]
Here we have the Physical
Operations Department.
The Physical Operations Department
handles logistics for the corporation.
Management of our properties...
Excuse me. I need
to use the restroom.
- Of course, Mr. Wayne. It's right here.
- Thank you.
[ALARM WAILING]
The Foxglove is in the old
Klondike Building on Mayflower.
- You score a ticket?
- Yep. But only one.
I figure you go in, pose as a john,
find something to bust them on...
then we squeeze
them till they talk.
Smart move sending me.
You couldn't look more like a
cop if you wore a blue uniform.
You got something to wear?
You're, uh, gonna need to fit in.
Don't worry. Alvarez busted some
guys smuggling Italian suits last week...
and a couple fell in my locker
on their way to the evidence room.
[CHUCKLES]
LENNON: I'm sorry
I left you alone...
but you needed time to think,
to accept that this was real.
This apartment is soundproof,
by the way, so save your lungs.
Look at me. My
hands are shaking.
That's never happened before with
any of the other women I've had here.
You know why that is?
Do you know why that is?
You're a psycho.
I don't know what
you're thinking.
It's because...
I always somehow
knew, deep down...
the others weren't the one.
They weren't the one.
I want this to work, Barbara.
You're scared. It's okay.
Jim will find me. Unh!
The only way you're going to make
me angry is if you mention his name.
Drink this.
It's water. You're dehydrated.
Barbara, come here. I
want you to see something.
Barbara, I love you. I love you
like no one has ever loved you.
But if you try to escape, I will
chain you to the ceiling and gut you.
Now come here.
Are those...?
When you're looking for love,
you have to kiss a lot of frogs.
Still, I should be thankful.
They led me to you.
All those women...
they died here?
You killed them...
here?
Yes.
Don't worry.
I'm gonna set you free.
You're the one, Barbara.
You're the one.
[ALARM WAILING]
[ALARM STOPS]
BUNDERSLAW: Hello, Bruce.
I've been expecting you.
Ever since your friend borrowed
my key, I've been expecting you.
Even canceled my trip.
Cookie?
When I was a boy...
I'd always take a cookie
when I had the chance.
You hired a man to kill Alfred.
I hired your guardian's comrade
to find out what you knew.
I never intended harm
to come to anyone.
I told the board you were a special
case, that you'd need the talk early.
The talk.
Bruce, when members of the
Wayne family reach a certain age...
some facts of life and
business are explained...
Wayne Enterprises is
committing serious crimes.
Oh, my, yes.
This is a multinational corporation
operating in hundreds of jurisdictions.
We do our best to subvert
all of them if it means profits.
- So you admit it?
- Just like your father.
He came in with his secret
files demanding justice...
at first.
Then he changed his mind.
You're lying.
Your father came to understand
the reality of this business.
As did his father,
and as will you.
My father was a good man.
You have an opportunity
to live a blessed life.
The life your father and
mother wanted for you.
I beg you to reconsider.
Pardon me.
Lucius, come in.
Bruce Wayne, meet one of
our junior executives, Lucius Fox.
There's a public-relations person
desperately searching for this young man.
Then you'd best reunite them.
Bruce.
Don't forget your cookie.
Now...
I'm going to tell you
something, and I'd
appreciate if you kept
your face perfectly still.
There's cameras everywhere. I
know because I put them there.
What I'm about to say must be a
deep secret between you and me.
I knew your father
well. He was good man.
He wasn't the man the
company thought he was.
- I don't understand you.
- Bruce.
Your father was a true stoic.
He kept his best self hidden.
That's all I'll say.
Good luck.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
KRISTEN: Mr. Nygma?
- Ms. Kring...
Ms. Kringle?
Would you open the door, please?
Um, I'm...
One sec.
I need the Hendricks case files.
Um, yes. Hendricks.
Wait right there.
Hendricks, Hendricks, Hendricks.
Hendricks!
Ahh. Oh, my goodness.
- What happened to him?
- Um, ax.
Accidental death.
At a sheet-metal
factory. Industrial saw.
[BUZZES]
Poor man.
I don't... I don't know
how you do this job.
- Death all around you.
- Heh.
Yes. One must have
a sense of humor.
- The file?
- Yes.
Um, Mr. Nygma.
You haven't by chance seen
Tom...? Officer Dougherty?
We were supposed to have
dinner last night, and he didn't show.
No surprise. But I
haven't seen him today.
Me neither.
Oh.
Excuse me. I really
need to get back to work.
Oh, uh.
- Now.
- Okay. Um...
Oh, dear.
You're sure the guns are there?
Butch placed them himself.
Do you remember what to say
to Maroni before you do the deed?
I never saw the point in
telling a man something...
right before you're
gonna whack him.
But you're not the
first to ask for it.
I appreciate you humoring me.
So how'd you know Maroni's
gonna be in this bar on this exact day?
I follow current events.
[CHUCKLES]
There he is. Tommy
freaking Bones.
Nine years up the river, and you
get better-looking, you big animal.
I took care of myself.
I was hoping you'd remember.
- Ha, ha.
- Come over here. Huh?
Listen, you leave the joint,
you come to Lidia's for dinner.
That's tradition. Welcome home.
Lidia. Look who's here.
[ALL LAUGHING]
[DANCE MUSIC
PLAYING ON SPEAKERS]
Welcome to the Foxglove. The
evening's entertainment is about to begin.
Well, I guess I'm just in time.
[PEOPLE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Ladies and gentlemen,
your attention, please.
I know you have been eagerly
awaiting tonight's main attraction.
So please, let's give a big Foxglove
welcome to Ingrid and Gareth.
[APPLAUSE]
[WHEELS SQUEAKING]
[INGRID MOANS THEN GIGGLES]
[ENGINE WHIRRING]
GARETH: Ow!
Oh, no.
Hell, no.
[PIG SQUEALS]
G.C.P.D.! Nobody move.
Especially you two.
Barbara.
Wake up, Barbara.
Wake up.
Shh, shh. Come here.
Don't cry. Shh. Shh.
Hey.
There's no need to cry, okay?
You're gonna kill me.
- Do you want me to?
- No.
Then tell me who to kill.
What?
You still don't believe I
love you. You think I'm crazy.
That's fine.
I see the truth.
I see your truth.
I see that you've spent your whole
life trying to kill it, but you can't.
It's too strong.
You revealed it to
me the other night.
I wanna set that free.
I wanna set you free.
You think that me making you
murder someone will make me like you?
That's insane.
You say that...
because you don't know
what it is to live without fear.
But you'll learn.
Now tell me who
you want me to kill.
Or though it breaks my heart,
I will take your life right now.
I can't.
I... I can't.
Tell me who to kill.
Okay.
You run this place?
I'm looking for this man.
Arrest me if you want to. I
don't talk about my clients.
One call to the Gazette, they'll
send a reporter down here.
I'll perp-walk each and every one of
your clients in front of the cameras.
How's that sound?
Talk to Sally.
You know him? You're sure?
I'm sure.
He said his name was
Jason. He was sweet.
As soon as I got into his car,
he pulled a hood over my head...
and tied my wrists.
He took me to back to his
apartment. That's where he did this.
I don't know why he let me go.
- When was this?
- Almost nine years ago.
About a year before the first
murder. He was working his way up.
Why didn't you go to the police?
I did. I was a hooker. He
was a rich man with no name.
Anything else you can tell us?
Anything about his apartment?
The smallest detail might help.
The elevator opened
right into the apartment.
You can see out into the
city. We were in midtown.
And there was a big neon sign
on the building across the street.
I could only read the
last four letters, O-Y-A-L.
O-Y-A-L.
- Loyal? Royal?
- Royal.
- The Gotham Royal Hotel.
- That's in midtown. Tenth and Gainsly.
Thank you, Sally.
Promise me, when you
find him, don't arrest him.
Kill him.
You got it.
- Making jokes already. He's out two hours.
- Whoa, fellas. Private party.
CONNOR: Just
here to pay respects.
MARONI: Connor
from the wild northeast.
What's that old man
Falcone want now?
Don Falcone sends
me with his respects...
and a small gift for you and
Tommy Bones on this happy day.
Cheech.
- Forgive my suspicious nature.
- Course. Can't be too careful.
Come here. Let me see this.
Madre Di Dios.
My favorite.
Tell Falcone I
appreciate the gesture.
Don Falcone knew it
was a special occasion.
We got time for a drink.
Lidia. Clean glasses, please.
- The gift comes with a message.
- Oh, yeah? What's that?
He wants you to know that it wasn't
easy for him to decide to kill you.
Son of a bitch.
But business is business.
[CLICKING]
You believe it?
You both jammed. If that ain't a
sign from God, I don't know what.
- Please...
- Shut your mouth.
You're gonna take Don
Falcone a message from me.
You're gonna let him
know that you messed up...
and you're gonna let him
know that I'm coming for him.
Of course, you don't need
to be alive to tell him that.
Tommy, do the honors.
Wait...
[SINGING] All you
punks and all you Teds
National Fronts and Natty Dreads
Mods, rockers,
hippies and skinheads
Keep on fighting
'til you're dead
Connor blew it.
Maroni's still alive.
This is flat.
Did you not hear me?
Maroni is still alive.
You gotta get out of town.
And miss all the fun?
You knew.
You set him up.
I took the firing pins out of
the guns before you hid them.
A spin on a trick I
learned from Maroni.
- But you could have had Maroni dead.
- True.
But I still would've been
under Falcone's thumb.
And that...
has grown intolerable.
No, I'd much rather
Maroni be alive...
and out for blood.
Alas, Officer Dougherty, she's
gonna wonder where you went.
Perhaps a letter?
You could say goodbye,
give her some advice.
Something that might lead her to
make better choices in the future, hmm?
[GRUNTING]
BULLOCK: Jim!
Place is empty.
But there's something
you should see.
You see anything that
connects to Barbara?
Maybe she was never here.
No, she was here. I can
still smell her perfume.
Hey. We're gonna find this guy.
But you need to
prepare yourself...
that we might not
be in time to save her.
- That is not an option.
- It's the most likely option.
[PHONE RINGING]
Hello?
LENNON: Detective Gordon.
I assume you're the one
who triggered the alarm.
You son of a bitch.
Where's Barbara?
With me, of course.
If you've hurt her...
She's as safe as milk.
Safer than she ever was
when she was with you.
- What the hell does that mean?
- She doesn't need your protection, Jim.
Fact is, she never did.
- I'll see you around.
- Wait.
- He was driving.
- To Tahiti if he's smart.
There was a noise, right?
A thumping.
- Like he was going over a bridge.
- You know, I heard a horn.
- Like a train horn.
- Okay. So which bridge has a train?
Um... Damn.
Whitecross. But
that's the upstate train.
Upstate?
That's where her parents live.
Barbara, please.
What's happening?
LENNON: What's happening is
your daughter is finally waking up.
Please?
Barbara, we're
doing this for you.
[WOMAN SCREAMS]
[JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING
INDISTINCTLY ON SPEAKERS]
I never meant to hurt you
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
Jim?
Barbara.
What are you doing here?
[GRUNTS]
You're not supposed to be here.
Where is he?
[BOTH GRUNTING]
Drop it. Drop the
knife, or I'll shoot.
Just an ounce of pressure,
and she'll split right open.
I don't want that.
Do you want that?
It's gonna be all right,
Barbara. It's gonna be all right.
If you cared about this woman,
you never would have come after me.
- I love her more than you ever did.
- Drop the knife.
It won't be me
that slits her throat.
Detective, that's gonna be you.
- Drop it.
- Jim, please.
Just leave us alone.
Hey. Jerk-o.
Barbara? Barbara?
- He's dead?
- Yeah. He's dead.
It's gonna be okay.
Look at me. Barbara.
Alfred, I never asked you...
how was it yesterday,
seeing Reggie?
Not really an experience I'd
care to repeat, Master Bruce.
But then again, the Reggie
I knew died years ago.
Alfred, I haven't
been honest with you.
After you were hurt...
Selina and I went
looking for Reggie.
We found him.
Did you, now?
He didn't jump or fall.
Selina pushed him.
And why did she do that?
Reggie was sent here by a
man named Sid Bunderslaw.
Bunderslaw works
for Wayne Enterprises.
Reggie gave us the name...
but said he was gonna tell
Bunderslaw what we were doing.
I see.
And the rest?
The charity ball?
Presumably to have
access to Mr. Bunderslaw.
Selina stole the
key to his office safe.
I went there
today. It was empty.
But Bunderslaw
was waiting for me.
- What did he do?
- Nothing.
But he said that my
father and grandfather...
knew about the illegal things that
the company was doing, and chose...
They chose to stay quiet.
[SIGHS]
Your father was a good man.
I know.
But even good men have secrets.
MAN 1: Good job. MAN 2: Yeah.
MAN 1: Very well
deserved. MAN 3: Well done.
- Man of the hour.
- Please.
MAN 3: Very well. MAN
4: That guy right there.
Congratulations. You're a hero.
It won't last. Tomorrow
they'll go back to hating me.
Well, then I'll remind them.
Yesterday you were trying to
help. I couldn't hear it. I'm sorry.
I would never try
to change you, Jim.
Your sense of mission, it's
part of what I love about you.
I thought it was my
devastating good looks.
That's a joke.
[LAUGHS]
I was scared.
Scared that Barbara
would get hurt...
and you would blame
yourself for protecting me first...
and then whatever
we had would die.
It wasn't heroic.
It was selfish.
Lee, I love you.
Not her.
If I had to do it again,
I'd still protect you first.
What did you do?
Grabbed a knife by the blade.
Of course you did.
- Let me see.
- Agh.
Ms. Kringle?
Are you okay?
I got a letter from
Officer Dougherty.
He left town.
[CLEARS THROAT]
"Don't wait around for
me. Go have some fun,
and maybe I'll give you
a call when I get back."
Blah-blah-blah. Couldn't
even tell me to my face.
I mean, why do I
keep picking creeps?
Sometimes with men, you
need to read between the lines.
Sometimes with
men, you need a drink.
Good day, Mr. Nygma.
Read between the lines.
[LAUGHING]
Everybody listen up.
Just got wind of three
separate attacks on
Falcone businesses in
different parts of town.
Word is it's Maroni.
As of right now, all
leaves are canceled
and all units are
called in for active duty.
We're in a shooting war, people.
[LAUGHING]
[English - US -SDH]